MATT DOW

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

651-587-8454 | matt.dow.vo@gmail.com | Minneapolis, MN | github.com/mattdow

ABOUT ME

I'm a full-stack software engineer with expertise in data analytics and open-source intelligence. In my previous career as a class-A commercial property manager, I successfully collaborated with accountants, lawyers, IT professionals, engineers, and contractors. I made a career change because I wanted to use my technical acumen to solve problems like the experts I had been working with. Outside of work, I'm a musician, a voiceover artist, and a trivia addict.

SKILLS/TECHNOLOGIES

JavaScript	Node.js	Express	React.js
Redux	Saga	PostgreSQL	REST API
Passport	Chart.js	HTML5	CSS3
Bootstrap	Material-UI	MS Excel	Tableau

WORK EXPERIENCE

Prime Digital Academy | Minneapolis, MN

August 2021 - Present

Full Stack Software Engineering Student

Solo Project: DiscTrac Disc Golf Score and Note Tracker

- Allows a user to record short notes as they play and score a round of disc golf. Hole notes from prior rounds are automatically retrieved and displayed while playing that hole.
- Users can upload new course and hole information from the Professional Disc Golfers Association API. The user profile shows summary statistics and charts of the users scores by round, course, and hole.
- Technologies used: Javascript, Node.js, Express, React.js, Redux, Saga, REST API, PostgreSQL, and Material-UI.

Ryan Companies | Minneapolis, MN

September 2011 – May 2020

Real Estate Manager

- Managed a 650,000 square foot class-A office building with two colleagues.
- Created a plan to sustain Ryan's culture as part of Ryan's 2015-16 Emerging Leaders Group.
- Raised over \$300,000 during dozens of events as co-ambassador of Ryan's 2016 United Way Week.
- Improved janitorial service, security, window cleaning, and elevator maintenance by crafting and enforcing contract language and regularly meeting with vendors.
- Spearheaded a major security audit, then used the findings from the audit to recreate the building's Emergency Management Plan and Tenant Warden Training.
- Facilitated a full lease turnover and four major tenant improvement projects over two years as lead manager for a small downtown office building.

MATT DOW

WORK EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

University of Maryland Medical Center | Baltimore, MD

July 2010 - June 2011

Human Resources – Educational Assistance Coordinator

- Disbursed tuition reimbursement, dependent tuition, and continuing education benefits for over 7,000 employees.
- Managed expectations of employees and guided them through the documentation requirements to ensure they received the appropriate assistance promptly.
- Analyzed all incoming personnel requisitions throughout the hospital to verify appropriate financial authorization for the hires.

R-Tech Laboratories (Land O' Lakes) | Arden Hills, MN

August 2008 - June 2010

Lab Technician

- Prepared and documented all incoming supplies and food samples to ISO 17025 standards.
- Tested food samples for moisture content and basic nutrient composition.

EDUCATION

Prime Digital Academy | Minneapolis, MN | Full Stack Software Engineering Certification

January 2022

• Prime Digital Academy is a full-time, accelerated immersion program in full-stack web software development. In addition to technical training, the Prime curriculum includes professional skills practice, public speaking, training in diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility, and many other career development skills.

General Assembly Online | Certificate in Data Analytics

May 2019 – Aug 2019

University of Wisconsin-Madison | Courses taken toward a Chemical Engineering degree

Sept 1997 – Dec 2001